CHRISTOPHER FARRELL

(518)275-3089 cxf1897@gmail.com

Software Engineer with knowledge in a variety of disciplines. Proven skills in software development, design, and maintenance. Experienced with designing software systems and planning for the future of those systems. Successful in communicating clearly with a variety of people and working in a team environment.

Education:

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, August 2015 - Rochester Institute of Technology

Experience:

Software Engineer - Oasis Systems, LLC.

Jun 2015 - Present

Worked in a team environment to develop software systems for the United States Air Force. Wrote front facing web pages which handled the writing to and displaying of information from a database. Reduced extrenuous calls to the database by 40%.

Technologies: Node.js, AngluarJS, Typescript, MongoDB, ZeroMQ, Express, Jade

Web Development Co-op - Nazareth College

Dec 2011 – Aug 2012

Developer for a variety of web applications for both internal and external use. Solely responsible for taking a project from gathering the requirements to releasing the application and maintaining the application after release. Worked directly with customers and stakeholders to ensure that the best possible product was being delivered.

Technologies: Linux, Python, Django, HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Sensors Results:

- Decreased the overhead for the Registrar's office.
- Increased transparency between Campus Safety and student body.

Software Engineering Teaching Assistant - RIT

Aug 2014 - Dec 2014

Helped teach a class of 22 students the basics of eliciting requirements from the customer to releasing a finished product.

Projects:

Virtual Meeting Outcome Facilitator (vMOF)

Created a one-page web application for the MITRE corporation that was designed to mitigate the common problems that arose during meetings. Improved meeting efficiency through a variety of tasks aimed to streamline the regular tasks that were performed during a meeting.

Activities:

New Student Orientation - RIT

Aug 2013/Aug 2014

Received extensive leadership training to help with the responsibility of incorporating 18 new students into the RIT community and helping them adjust to college.

Kappa Delta Rho Fraternity

Vice President - 2013 - Increased chapter membership by 20%